Guide to the Abraham Anson papers, 1939-2005
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Abraham Anson papers
1939-2005
C0069
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
12.5 linear feet (31 boxes)
The collection includes aerial photographs, publications, newspapers, magazines, correspondence, notebooks, color slides, glass slides, and maps.
Anson, Abraham, 1912-2005
Box 1-31
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Myra Anson-Nicholas on December 5, 2005.
Biographical Information
Born January 21, 1912 to Ida and Emil Anson, Abraham Anson attended New York City University before joining the army. During his service, Anson would attain the rank of Lieutenant Colonel as well as make significant contributions to the training of incoming recruits. He retired from the army on January 21, 1972. Anson was paramount in the designing of equipment with the Army Corps of Engineers that aided in mapping.
Anson was an incredibly active member with the American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing and also has a memorial scholarship in his name. Along with his significant contributions to the world of photogrammetry, the process of measuring distances between objects through the utilization of photography, Anson was extremely adept at surveying and mapping, and was a very talented painter. Abraham Anson passed away May 29, 2005.
Scope and Content
The collection includes numerous aerial photographs, publications, photography equipment, newspapers, magazines, correspondence, notebooks, color slides, and maps. The collection is arranged into three series.:
Series 1: Personal Items (1939-2005) includes notes, correspondence, academic records, memoirs, programs, and military records.
Series 2: Maps and Photographs (1940-2004) includes maps, color slides, glass slides, and photographs.
Series 3: Publications (1943-2005) includes books, magazines, reports, and manuscripts.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series.
Series 1: Personal Items, 1939-2005 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 2: Maps and Photographs, 1940-2004 (Boxes 4-12)
Series 3: Publications, 1943-2005 (Boxes 13-31)
Index Terms
Persons:
Anson, Abraham, 1912-2005
Subjects:
Aerial photographs.; Letters.; Maps.; Photogrammetry.; Photography.; Remote sensing.; Slides.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Glass negatives.; Maps.; Negatives.; Newspapers.; Photographs.; Slides.
Contents List
- Series 1: Personal Items, 1939-2005 (Boxes 1-3)
  This series includes notes, correspondence, academic records, and military records.
  - Publisher Correspondence (1 of 2), September 1970-August 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publisher Correspondence (2 of 2), December 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Application for Federal Employment, April 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with William Pryor, November 1975-January 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Department of Occupations and Professions Engineering Application, October 25, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Robert Colwell to Abraham Anson, May 7, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence About Pamphlet Design, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing-Potomac Region Board of Directors Meeting Notes, April 16, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Academic and Military Awards Belonging to Abraham Anson, 1971-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aerial Photography and Photogrammetry Materials Checklist, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Abraham Anson Project Notes, circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Supersonic Speed Aerial Photograph Exposure Test, May 10, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Supersonic Speed Aerial Photograph Conference Report, January 31, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Approved Script of Presentation on Making Concrete, June 13, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter To Abraham Anson About Commission, May 30, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, February 1973-July 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Army Engineer Topographic Laboratories Lecture, March 3, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes on Aerial Color Photography, November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Study Plan for the Effects of Supersonic and Hypersonic Aircraft Speeds Upon Aerial Photography, January 6, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Culvert Construction Approved Narration Script, July 26, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Convair Flight Test Notes, September 1958-December 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Keynote Address for Workshop In Aerial Color Photography, February 19, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence About Publication Reviews, June 1974-October 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters of Acknowledgement to Abraham Anson, December 1976-January 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - United States Civil Service Retirement System Membership Documents, March 1948 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with The American Society of Photogrammetry and Meeting Notes, July 1969-April 1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Watercolor Painting Of The Pentagon by Abraham Anson, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Certificate of Appreciation Awarded By the Potomac Region American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter From Who's Who in America, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Biographical Information on Abraham Anson, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence with The United States Department of the Interior, April-September 1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Genealogical Information for Abraham Anson, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and Biographical Information, June 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Abraham Anson's Memoirs, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - E-mail Correspondence with the American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, March 27, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Abraham Anson Department of Interior Employee Documents and Field Reports, August 1946-November 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Correspondence and U.S. Army Approved Narration Script on Concrete Construction, May 1960-October 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Commendations for Abraham Anson, June 1962-March 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - United States Army Management School Diploma and Photograph of Graduating Class, January 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Map Compilation Branch Report By Abraham Anson, October 17, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Retirement Payroll Information, January 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Universities and The American Society of Photogrammetry, May 1982-December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letters of Appreciation from the Geographic Intelligence Division, July 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - List of Paintings by Abraham Anson, July 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Instruction Certificates and Training Documents, April 1944-October 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence About Anson Publications, November 1988-December 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with Universities and The American Society of Photogrammetry about Photo Interpretation and Publications, June 1965-November 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - United States Army Personnel Records for Abraham Anson, 1948-1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, September 1961-March 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, September 1971-August 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography and Daily Activities in Switzerland, July 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography and Photogrammetry, May 1968-October 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, September 1965-April 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, November 1964-September 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, September 1959-September 1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Aerial Photography, October 1968-January 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Thank You note to Abraham Anson from David Martz, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sundicator Disposition Form, February 1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with the American Society of Photogrammetry, November 14, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lessons in Lettering Booklet, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence About Publications, 1967-2004 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clipping about Abraham Anson and Water coloring, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with R.H. Lyddan, May 15, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Kevin Flynn about Publications, April 8, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - GeoTech 2004 Conference Brochure, October 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Informed Consent for Myers Research Institute, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - List of American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Candidates Running for National Office, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Post 589 Roster, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Log Book of Abraham Anson During Research and Development at USAEGIMRADA, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Program for Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Program for Original Ballet Russe, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Program for Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Program for Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series 2: Maps and Photographs, 1940-2004 (Boxes 4-12)
  This series includes maps, slides, and photographs
  - NASA Photographs Taken In Space, circa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - United States Air Force Color Aerial Photographs, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Abraham Anson, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Contour Line System Photography, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - United States Army Vectograph Prints, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Map Index, and Aerial Photographs, July 1972-December 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Photographs, June 1959-November 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Key West Test- Maps and Photographs, circa 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Aerial Photographs and Flight Path Maps, February 1959-April 1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - United States Air Force Color Aerial Photographs, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Aerial Photographs and Flight Path Maps, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Aerial Photograph Negatives of Bennettsville, South Carolina, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - United States Air Force Color Aerial Photographs, circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of U.S. Soldiers in New Guinea, May 1943 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Negatives of Aerial Photographs of Potomac Shoreline, September-December 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Abraham Anson Presentation on Improving National Datasets, circa 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Potomac Region American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Potomac Region American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs (2 of 2), January 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Color Photographs from Arizona, June 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Black and White Photographs Taken at Fort Belvoir, 1944-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Topographic Maps of Kentucky and Photographs of the Shenandoah River, circa 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Topographic Maps of Kentucky, Puerto Rico, and Virginia, circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Abraham Anson, Kentucky, Puerto Rico, and Virginia, 1947-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations and Topographic Maps from "Mapping the Earth", circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Color Slides of Abraham Anson and Vacation, circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Maps of Greece and Soviet Union, December 1958, March 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Glass Slides of Automatic Mosaicker, circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Aerial Photographs of Southern Florida and British Columbia, circa 1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Photographs Taken at Fort Belvoir, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Multiband Cameras and Aerial Photographs of Telluride, Colorado, circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Watercolor Painting by Abraham Anson, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 11x10 inch Aerial Photograph Negatives, circa 1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 2.5x3.5 inch Negatives of Abraham Anson, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 11x10 inch Aerial Photograph Negatives, circa 1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Note cards and Sundicator from Presentation on Aerial Color Photography, circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 4x3 inch Glass Slides of Color Aerial Photography, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 4x3 inch Glass Slides for Photogrammetry, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 4x3 inch Glass Slides of Stereoscopic Effect of Color, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 4x3 inch Glass Slides of Brock Method, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 4x3 inch Glass Slides of Map Composition, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 4x3 inch Metal Negatives of Photogrammetry Equipment, circa 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Indexes to Topographic Maps of Kentucky and Virginia, November 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Aerial Photographs of Yosemite, circa 1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Color Aerial Photographs, circa 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photograph Negatives, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives (1 of 5), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives (2 of 5), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives (3 of 5), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives (4 of 5 ), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives (5 of 5), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Photographs Taken at a Technical Conference, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photograph Negatives, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Photogrammetry Instruments, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Photogrammetry Workshop and LAWDSAT Conference, 1995-1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Photographs Taken at a Technical Conference, October 1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs and Negatives, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs of Presenters (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Annual Meeting Photographs of Presenters (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - C.D. Pictures of Presenters and Attendees at "Tech 2002", 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Conference Photographs, February 1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Photographs taken at GeoTech 2001 Conference, October 16-17, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Aerial Photographs, Correspondence, and Topographic Maps, 1959-1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Landsat Photographs of North America, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Photogrammetry Equipment, circa 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Black and White Photograph from the Earth Resources Aircraft Project, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Black and White Photograph of Abraham Anson, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 8.5x11 inch Black and White Photographs of Abraham Anson, Fort Belvoir, and Photogrammetry Instruments, 1941-1965 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Abraham Anson, 1972-2002 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - General Electric Missile and Space Vehicle Department Map of the Moon, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Map of Hong Kong, June-July 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Landscape Photographs and Topographic Map of the Tyndall Creek Basin, circa 1945 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Color Aerial Photographs, circa 1960 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 8x11.5 inch Photograph of Incoming Officers of the American Society of Photogrammetry, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Earth Resource Mapping Promotional Poster, circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 4x6 inch Black and White Photograph of "Norvie", 1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Department of the Interior Map of Puerto Rico and the Virginia Islands, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 8.5x11 inch Black and White Photographs, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Color Aerial Photographs from Unknown Magazine, circa 1970 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 3x5 inch Color Photographs of Landscapes and Photogrammetry Equipment, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Topographic Map of Katahdin, Maine, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 3x5 inch Color Photographs of Landscapes and Photogrammetry Equipment (1 of 4), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 3x5 inch Color Photographs of Landscapes and Photogrammetry Equipment (2 of 4), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 3x5 inch Color Photographs of Landscapes and Photogrammetry Equipment (3 of 4), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 3x5 inch Color Photographs of Landscapes and Photogrammetry Equipment (4 of 4), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Geographic Maps, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 2x2 inch Slides of Aerial Photography, Automatic Mosaickers, and, Key West, and Photogrammetry Equipment, circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 2x2 inch Slides of Abraham Anson, Aerial Photography, and Photogrammetry Equipment, circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 4x3 inch Lantern Slides of Images from "The Stereoscopic Effect of Color", 1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 4x3 inch Lantern Slides of Bennettsville, South Carolina and Fort Belvoir, circa 1955 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 4x3 inch Lantern Slides of Images from "Non-Topographic Military Applications", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series 3:: Publications, 1943-2005 (Boxes 13-31)
  This series includes books, magazines, reports, and manuscripts.
  - "Significant Findings of a Stereoscopic Activity Study" by Abraham Anson, September 1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Non-Topographic Military Applications" by Abraham Anson and Topographic Photographs, August 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "Finding Your Way" Manuscript with Photos by Abraham Anson, January 1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "Feasibility of Objective Color Systems", September 13, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Materials Research And Standards, February 1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Color Aerial Photography in Photogenic Interpretation, September 1958 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Application of Color And Multispacial Techniques To The Collection Of Military Geographic Information, July 1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photogrammetry As A Science And As A Tool, January 1963 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Effects Of Supersonic And Hypersonic Speeds On Aerial Photography, circa 1960 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "An Automatic Mosaicking System" by Abraham Anson, July 1962 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Feasibility of Objective Color Systems, September 13, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "A Report On Several Projects at the U.S. Army Geodesy" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Army Geodesy, Intelligence, and Mapping Documents, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Finding Your Way" Draft by Abraham Anson with Illustrations, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Multispectral Experiment No. 2" By Abraham Anson, August 3, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Preservation of Photographs" Article by Eugene Ostroff, June 1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Commercial Remote Sensing Space Policies and Photographs, May 2003 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Manual of Remote Sensing" by The American Society of Photogrammetry, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry Newsletter, Number 2, April 1966 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Awards Program, April 24, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - "From Plane Table Topography to Photogrammetry" By Abraham Anson, circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Radarstat Product Guide, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - List of Publications Written by Abraham Anson, 1953-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "A Stereoscopic Acuity Study" By Abraham Anson, Pages 609-612, September 1959 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "The Use of Aerial Photography in the Reconnaissance of Soils and Rocks" By Abraham Anson, December 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "The Stereoscopic Effect of Color" Article By Abraham Anson, April 1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - "Developments in Aerial Color Photography For Terrain Evaluation" By Abraham Anson, January 1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with the American Society of Photogrammetry, March 1959-August 1962 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Information on Abraham Anson, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Drainage Maps of Bennettsville, South Carolina Test Area, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Memo Regarding Comparing Photointerpretation, August 1965 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - "On the Use on Infrared Emulsions for Photogrammetric Purposes" By Dr.-Ing H.K. Meir, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Evaluation of Phoenix Area Supersonic Photography, January 24, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Project Report on Supersonic Photography, January 20, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - "Manual of Color Aerial Photography" and Aerial Photograph Transparencies, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - "The Use of Aerial Photography in the Reconnaissance of Soils and Rocks" By Abraham Anson and Notes, December 1966-January 1967 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - "Developments in Aerial Color Photography For Terrain Evaluation" By Abraham Anson and Aerial Photographs, November 1966-September 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Wild RC 10 Universal Film Camera Manual, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Metric Qualities and Information Content of Aerial Color Photography: By Abraham Anson, June 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Comparative Photointerpretation From Panchromatic, Color And Ektachrome IR Photography" By Abraham Anson, February 1966 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Proposal for a Multiband Synoptic Photographic Experiment for Manner Earth Orbital Missions", March 18, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Photogrammetry as a Science and as a Tool (An Index)" Compiled By Abraham Anson, 1962-1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "The Stereoscopic Effect of Color" By Abraham Anson, Notes, and Aerial Photographs, July 1963-April 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "The Use of Color Aerial Photography in the Reconnaissance of Soils and Rocks" By Abraham Anson, Correspondence, and Photographs, June 1967-February 1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Comparative Photointerpretation Notes and Aerial Photographs, April 1958-February 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Comparative Photointerpretation From Panchromatic, Color, And Ektachrome IR Photography" By Abraham Anson, September 22, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Notes For Abraham Anson and Research Papers On Photogrammetry, circa 1962 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Publication Contributors, May-June 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Aerial Photography Equation Diagrams and Topographic Laboratory Instructional Film Script, circa 1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence, December 1962-December 1985 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with the American Society of Photogrammetry, circa 1976 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - "The American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, A History (1934 to 1991)" Pages 1-104, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "The American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, A History (1934 to 1991)". Pages 105-238, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 'The American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, A History (1934 to 1991)". Pages 239-338, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)